Guide to the Everett Education Association Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- United Teachers of Everett records, circa 1971-1986; 1973-1986; 3849-002; 22.00 cubic feet
  - Everett Education Association / Everett Federation of Teachers Unification, 1979-1980; Collection of letters, newsletters, ballots, and proposals to unify the Everett Education Association and Everett Federation of Teachers, creating United Teachers of Everett (UTE) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Everett Education Association Negotiations Information, 1979-1980; Contract analysis and development information and calendar, legal referral information summary of contract issues (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Everett Education Association End-of-the-Year Wrap-Ups, 1979-1980; Everett Education Association bi-laws, precinct caucus information, “Political Educator” “UniServ News” and “Your Public Schools” newsletters, year-end committee reports (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1979-1980; Meeting agendas and minutes (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1979-1980; Calendar of events, agendas, meeting minutes, letters and memos sent to the Representative Council (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1979-1980; Documents, newsletters, and memos published and available to all teachers including salary scale, election information, and conferences (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Everett Education Association End-of-the-Year Wrap-Ups, 1979-1980; United Teachers of Everett founding documents, committee reports, election procedures, contract information, annual goals (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Everett Education Association Membership Information, 1977-1980; Membership records, names of members by school, teachers by school and union / non-union affiliation, recruitment letters and strategies, Everett Education Association handbook (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Everett Education Association Political Action Committee, 1979; Letters and endorsements regarding political campaigns (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Everett Education Association Committee Information, 1979-1980; Committee reports for Instructional Theory, Contract Development, Grievances, and Community Action (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1979-1980; Monthly Everett Education Association budget reports (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Everett Education Association Committee Membership, 1979-1980; Lists of specific committee members (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Pilchuck UniServe Council Memos, 1979; Memos regarding recruitment, meeting times, and council staff contract (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Everett Education Association District-Wide Information, 1979; School names and contact information, list of Everett Education Association representatives and executive board members (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1979-1980; Documents, newsletters, and memos published and available to all teachers including salary scale, election information, and conferences (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Everett Education Association Committee Information, 1979-1980; Contract amendments, committee reports, press releases, and Everett Education Association Educational Philosophy (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1979-1980; Calendar of events, agendas, meeting minutes, letters and memos sent to the Representative Council (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Executive Board and Budget Information, 1979-1980; Meeting agendas, minutes, and budgets (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Everett Education Association Committee Information, 1979-1980; Committee reports for Instructional Theory, Contract Development, Grievances, and Community Action (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bargaining and Contract Proposals, 1979; Everett Education Association proposal for new contract and examples of contracts that they pulled from (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Everett Education Association Political Action and Grievance Committee Information, 1979-1980; Letters and endorsements regarding political campaigns, voting times, and grievance process (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Everett Education Association Membership Information, 1979-1980; Membership records, names of members by school, teachers by school and union / non-union affiliation, recruitment letters and strategies, Everett Education Association handbook (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1980-1981; Meeting agendas and minutes (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1980-1981; Calendar of events, agendas, meeting minutes, letters and memos sent to the Representative Council (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1980-1981; Monthly in reverse chronological order (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Everett Education Association Committee and Commissions Information, 1980-1981; Minutes, agendas, and supplementary information for the contract analysis, media relations, and newsletter committees (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1980-1981; Documents, newsletters, and memos published and available to all teachers including salary scale, election information, and conferences, some with pieces cut out (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1981-1982; Meeting agendas and minutes (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1981-1982; Calendar of events, agendas, meeting minutes, letters and memos sent to the Representative Council (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1981-1982; Monthly in reverse chronological order (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Everett Education Association Committee and Commissions Information, 1981-1982; Reports from several committees and hand written notes regarding proceedings (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - National Publications, Undated; outside organizational publications, copies of newspaper and magazine articles, teachers and air traffic controllers solidarity movement (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1981-1982; newsletters and contract information sent out and made available to all staff (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Workshop Information, 1981; organizational job descriptions, job changing workshop, student discipline and reward programs and evaluations (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1982-1983; meeting minutes and agendas in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1982-1983; meeting minutes and agendas in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1982-1983; monthly budget reports and annual budget plan (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Everett Education Association School Outreach, 1982; Grievance forms, Education Week information, microwave survey, political action volunteers (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1982-1983; newsletters and contract information sent out and made available to all staff in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Out-of District newsletters and flyers, 1982-1983; collection of national, state, and local newsletters and press releases received by the Everett Education Association (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Everett Education Association Labor Caucus, 1982-1983; labor caucus meeting minutes, memos and voting initiatives (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Snohomish County Labor Council, 1981-1982; Notes and memos regarding county-wide labor issues between different labor groups (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Political Movements and Information, 1982-1983; Roll-call vote results, list of contributors, memos and newsletters regarding legislative action (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Everett Education Association Newsletter Rough Drafts Part 1, 1982; Copies of newsletters cut up with edits and corrections to be copied into real newsletters, many pieces lightly stuck on and susceptible to falling off (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Everett Education Association Newsletter Rough Drafts Part 2, 1982; Copies of newsletters cut up with edits and corrections to be copied into real newsletters, many pieces lightly stuck on and susceptible to falling off (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1983-1984; meeting minutes and agendas in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1983-1984; meeting minutes, agendas, and attendance sheets in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Bargaining Alert Newsletters, 1983-1984; Specific newsletter collection about bargaining and how to successfully bargain for a contract (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Everett All-School Publications, 1983-1984; Newsletters and memos / letters put out by the Everett Education Association for members (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Out-of District newsletters and flyers, 1983-1984; Collection of newsletters, flyers, and articles sent to the Everett Education Association from local and state organizations and companies (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Political Movements and Information, 1983-1984; Memos and information on legislative actions regarding education, statements of support for public education from Senators and Vice President Mondale (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Everett Education Association Committee Information, 1983; Reports from Action Committee, Crisis Committee, and Strategy Committee (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Contract Negotiations Information, 1983; Letters and documents between teachers, the teachers unions, and families regarding bargaining issues and the contract negotiation process (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1984-1985; Meeting agendas and minutes in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1984-1985; Meeting agendas and minutes in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1984-1985; Monthly budget reports in reverse chronological order (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Everett Education Association Publications, 1984-1985; Everett Education Association newsletters and publications, most legal size (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Outside Publications, 1984-1985; Newsletters and flyers, primarily political and legislative, some relating to 1984 Mondale election (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Everett Education Association Executive Board Records, 1985-1986; Meeting minutes and agendas (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Everett Education Association Representative Council Records, 1985-1986; Meeting minutes and agendas (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Everett Education Association Budget Reports, 1984-1986; Itemized lists of expenditures within the Everett Education Association (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Everett Education Association Publications, 1985-1986; Newsletters and letters available to all teachers from the Everett Education Association (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Outside Political Publications, 1985-1986; Newsletters from government organizations or with political interests, middle corners bumpy (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Bargaining Information, 1983-1986; Letters and information regarding contract negotiations, copies of hand-written information and originals (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 1, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 2, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 3, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 4, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 5, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 6, 1978-1981; Mock-ups of newsletters, flyers, letters, etc. produced by the Everett Education Association. Pieces stuck on poorly, many loose edges. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Everett Education Association Newsletter Mock-Ups Part 1, 1984-1985; Mock-ups of Shockwaves and other Everett Education Association publications. Many pieces / newspaper clippings stuck on poorly and don't lay flat (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Everett Education Association Newsletter Mock-Ups Part 2, 1984-1985; Mock-ups of Shockwaves and other Everett Education Association publications. Many pieces / newspaper clippings stuck on poorly and don't lay flat (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 1, 1983-1984; Mock-ups of newsletters and information sent out to teachers, some pieces glued on and coming off (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Everett Education Association Publication Master Layouts Part 2, 1983-1984; Mock-ups of newsletters and information sent out to teachers, some pieces glued on and coming off (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Everett Education Association Masters for Publication Part 1, 1985-1986; Final drafts of newsletters and letters sent out to teachers, in fairly good condition, few loose pieces (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Everett Education Association Masters for Publication Part 2, 1985-1986; Final drafts of newsletters and letters sent out to teachers, in fairly good condition, few loose pieces (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Washington Labor Legislation, Undated; Copies of proposed Washington state legislation governing issues brought before the Public Employment Relations Commission (Washington Administrative Code 391-08), collective bargaining in Education (WAC 391-30), and a summary of these laws. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Everett School Board Initiated Proposals, 1969; Copies of contract negotiation points from the Everett School District to the teachers (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Salary Survey and information, 1969; Edmonds Education Association salary survey, copies of Everett salary survey and instructional memo “to determine degree of support” (on original file folder) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Everett School Board Contract Proposal, 1971; Copies of the Everett School Board’s contract proposal for teachers with memo from Everett Education Association President Chuck Olson (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Negotiations Packages, 1969-1970; History of negotiations, report on negotiations, lists of items to negotiate in fall 1969 and spring 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Original Everett Education Association Contract Proposal, 1969; Copy of Everett Education Association contract proposal with carbon copy of memo regarding content (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Contract Negotiations and Agreement, 1969; Different versions of the contract, with hand-written corrections on them as negotiations progressed (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Everett Calendar and Salary Schedule, 1970-1971; Copy of district calendar and teachers salaries / hiring practices (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Everett Education Association 1st Draft of Contract Proposal, 1970-1971; First draft of Everett Education Association contract with comments on each portion of the existing contract (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Everett Education Association Contract Negotiations and Impasse Reports, 1969-1971; Letters to school board and explanation for lack of agreement, carbon copies and typed copies of documents, one hand-written letter (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Everett Salary Schedules, 1970-1972; Salary schedules for administrators, school nurses, and teachers for 1970 to 1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Negotiations Calendar, 1970-1972; Calendars by dates and months outlining what needs to be done in the contract negotiations process (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Staff Surveys, 1971-1972; Collection of surveys sent out to teachers regarding salaries and other factors for contract negotiations (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Negotiation Committee Reports, 1971-1972; Reports from Professional Rights and Responsibilities committee, Improvement of Instruction Committee, and salary committee with recommendations for negotiations, two copies of each (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Proposed Salary Schedule, 1971; Copies of different salary schedules and memos regarding them (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Everett Education Association Original Contract Proposal, 1971; Formal contract proposal presented to the Everett School Board by the Everett Education Association with contract sections allowing for collective bargaining (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Certificated Staff Handbook, 1971; Copy of and memos regarding the handbook for teachers outlining general policies, teaching rights, and contract information (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1972-1973 Contract Negotiations, All Documents and information regarding contract negotiations, many hand written pieces and carbon copies with lots of blotches and fading ink (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Special Levy Salaries, 1971; Copies and memos regarding new salaries and ground rules for negotiations (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Everett Teacher's Contract, 1971; Contract for Everett teachers to sign for 1971 – 1972 school year (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Everett Teacher's Handbook and Tentative Contract Agreement, 1972-1973; Tentative contract agreement for 1973-1974 school year and teacher’s handbook for 1972-1973 school year (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Power of Attorney for Contract Negotiation, Undated; sample documentation giving Everett Education Association power to negotiate contracts for teachers (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - School Board Contract Proposal, 1972; Original contract given to Everett Education Association for the contract of the 1972-1973 school year with school calendar (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Salary Settlement, 1971; Copies of salary scale, explanation of salary changes, some fading carbon copies of memos (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Everett School District Calendars, 1960-1973; School calendars and note regarding their importance / significance (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Contract Negotiations Process, 1972-1973; Analysis of negotiations process, typed and hand-written documents (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Salary and Welfare Commission Reports, 1972; Documents explaining need for salary increase and how it affects teachers with benefits in comparison to other school districts (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Everett Education Association Priorities Survey, 1973; Handwritten survey results regarding teachers priorities for contract negotiations (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Reduction in School Funding, 1971-1972; Material planning for reduction in funding, staff lay-offs, etc. in the event that levies do not pass, includes legal documents and hand-written analysis (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Everett Education Association Contract Proposal, 1972; copy of Everett Education Association contract proposal with memo explanation (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Negotiation Notes, 1972; Handwritten notes describing the negotiation process and providing a transcript of the discussions (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Complete Teacher's Handbook, 1972; Bound handbook with contract information and teachers rights and responsibilities (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Salary Agreement, 1972; Faded carbon copies and tables of salary schedules and description of benefits (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - School Board Proposals, 1973; Proposals from school board regarding staff reduction and evaluation methods (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Teacher Ideas and Feedback, 1973; Hand-written suggestions by teachers to the Everett Education Association as requested for collective bargaining (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Everett Education Association Contract Counter Proposals, 1973; Counter proposals to district contract as negotiations go on, focus on maternity leave, grievances, and curriculum development (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - 1973 Contract Agreement, Two copies of the tentative contract agreement for 1973-1974 school year (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Principal Unions, 1973; Documents from Superintendent of Public Instruction allowing for principals to form their own unions (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Everett Education Association Negotiations Proposal, 1974; Copy of the Everett Education Association contract proposal from spring 1974 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - School Board minutes, 1975; Copy of the Everett school board minutes from March 31 1975 regarding salaries (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Task Force Negotiations, 1974; Copies of surveys regarding teacher priorities in the contract process (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Reduction in Force Negotiations, 1974; Negotiations between school board and Everett Education Association as a result of funding cuts (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Reduction in Force Evaluation Notes, 1973-1974; Handwritten notes transcribing the reduction of force discussions, ranging from December 19, 1973 to April 24, 1974. The first three sessions are on removed notebook paper, and sessions 4 to 21 are in a spiral bound notebook. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Everett Education Association and Everett School District Tentative Agreements, 1974; Tentative agreements between the Everett Education Association and Everett school district regarding evaluations and contracts, three copies of each document (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Everett Education Association v. Everett School District, 1974; Copy of court ruling between the Everett Education Association and Everett school district regarding the district’s refusal to negotiate contracts (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Everett Education Association Contracts and Handbook, 1974-1977; Everett Education Association tentative contract agreement, copy of the teacher’s handbook, Everett Education Association proposed contract, master copy of the contract, and representative council notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Everett Education Association Contract Negotiations Plan, 1974; Lists of representatives and contact people, as well as a collection of copies of petitions urging the Everett School District to meet with the Everett Education Association for contract negotiations (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Job Position and Contract Descriptions, 1975; Copies (printed and carbon) of certain job positions, their contracts, and legal mandates. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Everett Education Association Contract Negotiations, 1975; Copies and handwritten notes regarding contract negotiations, tentative contracts, and ground rules for contract negotiations (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Everett School District Contracts, 1975; Copies of tentative and master contracts for the 1975-1977 school years, including coaches salaries and job expectations (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Certified Teachers Information, 1975; Copy of lists of all teachers with their birthdates, certifications and year of graduation (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Contract Negotiations, 1973-1975; Discussions about contract timeliness, handwritten and photo-copied notes about contract negotiations and rules of procedure, survey and survey results (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Everett Contract Debate, 1975; Bargaining meeting minutes and agendas with notes and annotations, Everett Education Association specific contract proposals and district counter-proposals (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Everett Contract Proposals, 1976; Binder with detailed contract proposals, responses, and calendar agreements (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Everett Bargaining Election Part 1, 1975; Information from the bargaining election process, includes surveys, election rules, election results, and analysis (Box 8, Folder 10)